Outer Banks History Center Ephemera Collection PC.5276
State Archives of North Carolina
- State of North Carolina, 1825-2016 and undated; 43991; Outer Banks History Center
  - State Agencies and Organizations, 1850-2015 and undated; 4671; Outer Banks History Center
    - North Carolina Forestry Association, 1928-1990s; 5376; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Forestry Association)
    - North Carolina Genealogical Society, 1988-2007; 5377; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Genealogical Society)
    - North Carolina House of Representatives, 1965, 1997; 5378; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina House of Representatives)
    - North Carolina League of Conservation Voters, 1984; 5379; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina League of Conservation Voters)
    - North Carolina League of Municipalities, 1939-1967; 5380; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina League of Municipalities)
    - North Carolina Library Association, 1939-2004; 5381; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Library Association)
    - North Carolina Library Commission, 1929-1940; 5382; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Library Commission)
    - North Carolina Literary and Historical Association, 1905-2006; 5383; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Literary and Historical Association)
    - North Carolina Maritime History Council, 1990-2013; 5384; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Maritime History Council)
    - North Carolina Merchants Association, 1911-1922; 5385; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Merchants Association)
    - North Carolina Motor Carriers Association, 1956; 5386; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Motor Carriers Association)
    - North Carolina Museum of Art, 1974-2000; 5387; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Museum of Art)
    - North Carolina Museum of History, 1989-2006; 5388; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Museum of History)
    - North Carolina Museum of Natural Sciences, 1993-1995 and undated; 5389; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Museum of Natural Sciences)
    - North Carolina National Estuarine Research Reserve, 1997 and undated; 5390; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina National Estuarine Research Reserve)
    - North Carolina Nature Conservancy, 1979-2003; 5391; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Nature Conservancy)
    - North Carolina Postal History Commission, 1998; 5392; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Postal History Commission)
    - North Carolina Press Association, 1932-1946; 5393; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Press Association)
    - North Carolina Preservation Consortium, 1991-2006; 5394; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Preservation Consortium)
    - North Carolina Senate, 1891-1987; 5395; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Senate)
    - North Carolina Society Colonial Dames XVII Century, 1994-2000; 5396; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Society Colonial Dames XVII Century)
    - North Carolina Society of County and Local Historians, 1961-1985; 5397; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Society of County and Local Historians)
    - North Carolina Society for the Preservation of Antiquities, 1948-1961; 5398; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Society for the Preservation of Antiquities)
    - North Carolina State Ports Authority, 1989 and undated; 5399; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina State Ports Authority)
    - North Carolina Symphony, 1944-1997; 5400; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Symphony)
    - North Carolina Tuberculosis Association, 1920; 5401; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Tuberculosis Association)
    - North Carolina Wildlife Federation, 1991-1994; 5402; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Wildlife Federation)
    - Office of Environmental Education, 1985-1992; 5403; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Office of Environmental Education)
    - Office of the Governor, 1984-2001; 5404; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Office of the Governor)
    - Office of the Superintendent of Common Schools, 1854-1858; 5405; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Office of the Superintendent of Common Schools)
    - Office of the Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1869-1959; 5406; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Office of the Superintendent of Public Instruction)
      - Public School Law, 1903-1923; 23112; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Public School Law)
      - Reports, 1869-1959; 23113; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Reports)
    - Philanthropic Groups, 1898-1999; 5407; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Philanthropic Groups)
    - Political Groups, 1964-2004; 5408; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Political Groups)
    - Prison Department, circa 1957; 5409; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Prison Department)
    - Prohibition and Temperance Groups, 1908-1977; 5410; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Prohibition and Temperance Groups)
    - Rebekah Assembly, 1980-1989; 5411; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Rebekah Assembly)
    - Religious Groups, 1944-1999 and undated; 5412; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Religious Groups)
    - Republican Party, 1974; 5413; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Republican Party)
    - Research Triangle Foundation, 1959-1965; 5414; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Research Triangle Foundation)
    - Society of North Carolina Archivists, 1995-2006; 5415; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Society of North Carolina Archivists)
    - Sons of the American Revolution, 1908-1944; 5416; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Sons of the American Revolution)
    - Southern Albemarle Association, 1936-1996; 5417; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Southern Albemarle Association)
      Includes the official program for the dedication of the Herbert C. Bonner Bridge spanning Oregon Inlet, 2 May 1964.
    - Southern Oral History Organization, 1995; 5418; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Southern Oral History Organization)
    - State Advertising Division, circa 1950s-1960s; 5419; Outer Banks History Center
      - Publications, circa 1950s-1960s; 23114; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Publications)
      - Variety Vacationland, circa 1950s-1960s; 23115; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Variety Vacationland)
      - Variety Vacationland [2 folders], circa 1950s-1960s; 23116; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Variety Vacationland [2 folders])
    - State Archives, 1986-1994; 5420; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State Archives)
    - State Board of Elections, undated; 5421; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State Board of Elections)
    - State Board of Examiners, 1898; 5422; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State Board of Examiners)
    - State Capitol Foundation, 1980-1992; 5423; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State Capitol Foundation)
    - State Employees Combined Campaign, 1994; 5424; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State Employees Combined Campaign)
    - State Highway Commission, 1960-1968; 5425; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State Highway Commission)
    - State Historic Preservation Office, 1987-1993; 5426; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State Historic Preservation Office)
    - State Library, circa 1907-1998; 5427; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State Library)
    - State News Bureau, 1950-1952; 5428; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State News Bureau)
    - State Travel Bureau, 1953-1958; 5429; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State Travel Bureau)
    - State Travel Information Division, circa 1960s; 5430; Outer Banks History Center (Folder State Travel Information Division)
    - Tar Heel Club, 1927; 5431; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Tar Heel Club)
    - Travel and Promotion Division, circa 1960s-1970s; 5432; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Travel and Promotion Division)
    - Travel Development Section, 1975-1984; 5433; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Travel Development Section)
    - Travel and Tourism Division, 1984-1986; 5434; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Travel and Tourism Division)
    - Travel and Tourism Division: Camping and Outdoors Directories, circa 1950s-1980s; 5435; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Travel and Tourism Division: Camping and Outdoors Directories)
    - Travel and Tourism Division: Golf State U.S.A, circa 1960s-1980s; 5436; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Travel and Tourism Division: Golf State U.S.A)
    - United Daughters of the Confederacy, 1903-1931; 5437; Outer Banks History Center (Folder United Daughters of the Confederacy)
    - Utilities Commission, 1940-1994; 5438; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Utilities Commission)
    - Vocational Groups, 1915-1998; 5439; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Vocational Groups)
    - Wildlife Resources Commission, 1979-2006; 5440; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Wildlife Resources Commission)
    - Women's Society of Christian Service, 1955-1972; 5441; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Women's Society of Christian Service)
  - Events, 1866-2003 and undated; 4672; Outer Banks History Center
    The Events subseries, 1866-2003, contains materials related to anniversaries, celebrations, cultural events, memorials, unveilings, and conferences held in the state of North Carolina. Materials include programs, fliers, speech transcripts, and calendars. Of note in this subseries are programs from numerous state fairs and exhibitions, including the North Carolina State Fair.
    - Birthday Tributes and Commendations, 1907-1960; 5442; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Birthday Tributes and Commendations)
    - Central Carolina Fair, 1900-1905; 5443; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Central Carolina Fair)
    - Coastal Celebration, 1992; 5444; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Coastal Celebration)
    - Culture Week [2 folders], 1939-1959; 5445; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Culture Week [2 folders])
    - Culture Week [5 folders], 1960-1987; 5446; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Culture Week [5 folders])
    - Event Posters, 1922-1979 and undated; 5447; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Event Posters)
    - Fair of the Carolinas, 1871; 5448; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Fair of the Carolinas)
    - Memorial Addresses [4 folders], 1866-1955; 5449; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Memorial Addresses [4 folders])
    - North Carolina Calendar of Events, 1974-1984; 5450; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Calendar of Events)
    - North Carolina Calendar of Events, 1985-2003; 5451; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Calendar of Events)
    - North Carolina Day [3 folders], 1901-1919; 5452; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Day [3 folders])
    - North Carolina Exhibitions, 1883-1964; 5453; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Exhibitions)
    - North Carolina State Fair, 1884-1924; 5454; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina State Fair)
    - North Carolina State Fair [4 folders], 1951-1968; 5455; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina State Fair [4 folders])
    - Portrait Presentations [2 folders], 1899-1973; 5456; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Portrait Presentations [2 folders])
    - Tar Heel Writers Roundtable, 1975; 5457; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Tar Heel Writers Roundtable)
    - Unveilings and Monument Dedications, 1900-1962; 5458; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Unveilings and Monument Dedications)
    - Water Seminar, 1964; 5459; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Water Seminar)
  - Recreation, 1915-2001; 4673; Outer Banks History Center
    This subseries contains materials related to travel and tourism throughout the state of North Carolina. The bulk of the subseries consists of travel brochures for various regions in the state.
    - Travel Brochures: Albemarle Region, 1959-2001; 5460; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Travel Brochures: Albemarle Region)
    - Travel Brochures: Cape Fear Region [2 folders], circa 1960s-1998; 5461; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Travel Brochures: Cape Fear Region [2 folders])
    - Travel Brochures: North Carolina Mountains, 1915-1974; 5462; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Travel Brochures: North Carolina Mountains)
    - Travelers Almanac, 1993-1995; 5463; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Travelers Almanac)
  - Political Ephemera, 1825-2016 and undated; 4674; Outer Banks History Center
    The Political Ephemera subseries contains campaign flyers, propaganda, and circulars relating to state and national elections held in North Carolina. The folder of Campaign Materials and Propaganda, 1845-1898 and undated (box 79), primarily contains political circulars in support of particular candidates or campaign platforms, including two pieces of Reconstruction-era white supremacist propaganda: a statement on the "Lessons of the Wake Republican Convention" of 1898 warning against black citizens rising to power within the Republican party and a circa 1870s resolution passed by the conservative white citizens of Cross Creek Township praising congressional candidate Alfred Moore Waddell for his opposition to civil rights and social equality for African Americans.
    - Campaign Materials and Propaganda, 1845-1896 and undated; 5464; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Campaign Materials and Propaganda)
    - Campaign Materials and Propaganda, 1900-1947; 5465; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Campaign Materials and Propaganda)
    - Campaign Materials and Propaganda, 1952-1984; 5466; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Campaign Materials and Propaganda)
    - Campaign Materials and Propaganda, 2014; 5467; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Campaign Materials and Propaganda)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Materials, 1964-1984; 5468; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Gubernatorial Campaign Materials)
    - North Carolina House Campaign Materials, 1964-1976 and undated; 5469; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina House Campaign Materials)
    - North Carolina Judiciary Campaign Materials, 1968-1974; 5470; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Judiciary Campaign Materials)
    - North Carolina Senate Campaign Materials, 1984, 2016; 5471; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Senate Campaign Materials)
    - Political Circulars, 1825-1872; 5472; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Political Circulars)
    - United States Congressional Campaign Materials, 1900-1994; 5473; Outer Banks History Center (Folder United States Congressional Campaign Materials)
- University of North Carolina System, 1857-2010; 43992; Outer Banks History Center
  This series contains materials created by the University of North Carolina System and its individual campuses, primarily the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, the University of North Carolina at Greensboro, and North Carolina State University, and East Carolina University. Documentation of individual schools primarily consists of printed material distributed to current and prospective students, such as handbooks, directories, promotional brochures, commencement programs, and informational circulars. This series also includes a folder of material related to the consolidation of the University of North Carolina System, circa 1930s-1948.
  - Board of Trustees, 1957-1964; 5474; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Board of Trustees)
  - Consolidation, circa 1930s-1948; 5475; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Consolidation)
  - East Carolina University, 1966-2004; 5476; Outer Banks History Center (Folder East Carolina University)
    - Brochures and Event Flyers, 1966-2004; 23117; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Brochures and Event Flyers)
    - Division of Continuing Education, 1968-1996; 23118; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Division of Continuing Education)
    - Program Flyers, 1966-1990s; 23119; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Program Flyers)
    - Regional Development Institute, 1990s; 23120; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Regional Development Institute)
    - Summer Theater, 1966-2001; 23121; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Summer Theater)
  - Elizabeth City State University, 1991-2004; 5477; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Elizabeth City State University)
  - Institute of Statistics, 1948-1961; 5478; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Institute of Statistics)
  - North Carolina School of the Arts, 1995-2003; 5479; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina School of the Arts)
  - North Carolina State University, 1926-2004; 5480; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina State University)
    - Campus Buildings, 1950-1955; 23122; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Campus Buildings)
    - Colleges and Schools, 1950-1966; 23123; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Colleges and Schools)
    - Sea Grant Program, 1976-2004; 23124; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Sea Grant Program)
    - Sport Fishing School, 1957-2004; 23125; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Sport Fishing School)
    - Student Handbooks, 1926, 1957; 23126; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Student Handbooks)
  - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1857-2010; 5481; Outer Banks History Center
    - Alumni Association, 1881-1946; 23127; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Alumni Association)
    - Athletics and Physical Education, 1943-1963; 23128; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Athletics and Physical Education)
    - Board of Trustees, 1881-1961; 23129; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Board of Trustees)
    - Campus Buildings, 1927-1996; 23130; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Campus Buildings)
    - Campus Events, 1889-1975; 23131; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Campus Events)
    - Carolina Playmakers, 1916-1953; 23132; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Carolina Playmakers)
    - Carolina Symposium, 1956-1970; 23133; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Carolina Symposium)
    - Class Reunion Programs [2 folders], 1914-1968; 23134; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Class Reunion Programs [2 folders])
    - Commencement Programs [5 folders], 1857-1979; 23135; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Commencement Programs [5 folders])
    - Directories [5 folders], 1937-1952; 23136; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Directories [5 folders])
    - Directories [5 folders], 1953-1965; 23137; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Directories [5 folders])
    - Faculty and Administration, 1915-1980; 23138; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Faculty and Administration)
    - Inauguration Programs, 1885-1966; 23139; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Inauguration Programs)
    - Institute of Outdoor Drama, 1973-2010; 23140; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Institute of Outdoor Drama)
    - Institute for Human Relations, 1927-1945; 23141; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Institute for Human Relations)
    - Libraries, 1912-2005; 23142; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Libraries)
    - Music Department Programs, 1939-1952; 23143; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Music Department Programs)
    - Music Department Programs [3 folders], 1956-1965; 23144; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Music Department Programs [3 folders])
    - North Caroliniana Society, 1978-2003; 23145; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Caroliniana Society)
    - Office of Admissions, circa 1880s-1962; 23146; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Office of Admissions)
    - Oliver Max Gardner Award, 1949-1964; 23147; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Oliver Max Gardner Award)
    - Student Handbooks, 1895-1925; 23148; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Student Handbooks)
    - Student Handbooks [3 folders], 1927-1942; 23149; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Student Handbooks [3 folders])
    - University Day Programs, 1936-1963; 23150; Outer Banks History Center (Folder University Day Programs)
  - University of North Carolina at Greensboro [2 folders], circa 1907-1998; 5482; Outer Banks History Center (Folder University of North Carolina at Greensboro [2 folders])
  - The University in the War, 1942; 5483; Outer Banks History Center (Folder The University in the War)
- United States, 1932-2016; 43993; Outer Banks History Center
  This series contains materials created by national and federal organizations, as well as material related to the state of Virginia. Materials primarily consist of pamphlets, brochures, published reports, public notices, and form letters. Most of the materials in this series relate directly or indirectly to the North Carolina coastal region. The first two folders in the series document a proposed plan by Mobile Oil Company to conduct offshore drilling off the coast of North Carolina in the early 1990s. The United States Postal Service Commemorative Postage primarily commemorates significant events in coastal North Carolina history, such as the birth of Virginia Dare and the Wright Brothers' first flight.
  - Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries, 1989-1990; 5484; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries)
  - Materials Management Service Offshore Drilling Proposal, 1989-1990; 5485; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Materials Management Service Offshore Drilling Proposal)
  - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), 1981-2011; 5486; Outer Banks History Center (Folder National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA))
  - National Park Service, 1999-2016; 5487; Outer Banks History Center (Folder National Park Service)
  - United States Coast Guard Aids to Navigation Branch, 1927-1980; 5488; Outer Banks History Center (Folder United States Coast Guard Aids to Navigation Branch)
  - United States Geological Survey, 1948-circa 1990s; 5489; Outer Banks History Center (Folder United States Geological Survey)
  - United States Lighthouse Society, 1988-2003; 5490; Outer Banks History Center (Folder United States Lighthouse Society)
  - United States Postal Service Commemorative Postage, 1932-2016; 5491; Outer Banks History Center (Folder United States Postal Service Commemorative Postage)
  - Virginia, 1987-2005; 5492; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Virginia)
    - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 1987-1997; 23151; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation)
    - Life-Saving Museum of Virginia, 1989-2005; 23152; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Life-Saving Museum of Virginia)
    - Tidewater Genealogical Society, 1990-1995; 23153; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Tidewater Genealogical Society)